that's one thing I will give Zionists is they
are committed okay that is a committed cause
people out there tell your significant
others you commit like a Zionist okay
get down on your knees put that ring out and
you commit like a for 75 years or yeah yeah
yeah welcome to Friday night semites where we
actually know what a Semite is do you know what
a Semite is Josh um a little bit I do know that
that's the question that everyone's been asking
me since I told him the title of this show yeah
um so what do you tell him I tell him I'm going to
ask my co-host Samuel B so uh yeah I mean people
most people think Semite they think uh Jew but I
know it's a little bit broader than that so why
don't you tell us what you know well I'll tell
you I mean I'm I'm a math guy right so whenever
I whenever I used to hear semi or anti-semite I
would be like are these people against semicircles
or what like what is it you know what I mean yeah
cuz semi it comes from the I mean this has the
same roote as semi which is like partial right
right so I feel like we have partial information
on this situation so this this is what I know of
the history and I know you can break it down
for me so I know that the term Semite started
in the 1800s uh it was in the 1700s actually
thank you for the math correction all right
obviously we got a fact Checker here partial
information there it is so it started in the
1700s and like by a German linguist yeah which
is always start yeah where the problem started
here he was trying to break up different
linguistic groups and uh like a good racist
German um which is my favorite kind uh you
said it not me yeah yeah yeah I for sure I
said it h he broke it down into there was the
Aryan languages this is and then there was the
ham the Aryan languages was like northern and
western Europe of course there was the hamite
languages which was like North African um and
then there was the setic languages I'm glad
they separated the ham from the stics yeah got to
keep it kosher so um and so the Semitic languages
I know it was Hebrew but also Arabic also shout
out to Aramaic amaric a lot of other ones and
so I know that that's where citic comes from
but then because it was Germany in the 1700s
they were mostly talking about the Jews for
the semites and so that's why anti-semite
mostly came you jump some steps okay so so 1700s
the guy was like all right semites this is how
we distinguish the different races based on their
languages specifically they wanted to distinguish
other races from the Aryan race said listen we're
from Aryan Heritage these are this is something
the semites like you included those languages the
main two obviously being Hebrew and Arabic those
are the ones that most people speak I mean Aramaic
was a thing wasn't really huge at that time like
unless you know Jesus directly it's not really
about shout out to my Assyrians Yeah couple couple
still out there yeah and then of course a lot of
people you know there's some Ethiopian people who
speak Semitic languages as well a couple right
so um so that was his distinguish and so that was
like subtle racism it was like let's distinguish
let's classify right the problem started in uh the
1800s when a French scholar published a paper that
flat out said the Aryan races are better than the
citic races yeah that's usually what they used
to say and sometimes still but he was published
I mean like racism back in the day was like legit
it was accredited yeah yeah so so he says that he
says he said in every way semetic is inferior to
areas so then how did CTIC only get to be today
thought about with Jews so so at the time again he
was just talking about all Semitic peoples right
at this time the the racism was there but it was
it was all it was all inclusive you know what I
mean yeah it was it was yeah it was inclusive
racism so he publishes that um a an Austrian
scholar a Jewish Austrian scholar Okay saw that
paper and was like Hey guys does anybody notice
that's a little racist yeah yeah yeah and so he
coins the term anti-semite an Austrian version of
it I think it's like anti-semitic or something I I
don't speak Austrian me either but that was close
enough pretty good I feel pretty good yeah um I
just think I just think of like Arnold you know
like ah anti-semites you know like I think of
Arnold when I think of anti-semites too and his
father yeah yeah yeah so in Austria a a Jewish
scholar says he makes his term uh basically the
the root which eventually becomes anti-emetic yeah
and he is like this is what you call somebody who
hates the semetic races whether it's you know
people who speak Hebrew people who speak Arabic
whatever all the semetic races he coins that
term the Germans hear that they hear because
he publishes that right he's like from here on out
anybody who hates a Semitic races will be called
anti-semitic and the Germans are like yeah I like
that there's a name for our type of hate yeah we
want a name for it yeah you're like finally like
somebody who makes this sound professional you
know and so the Germans specifically the Nazis as
time went on and the Nazis came about they started
to self identify as anti-semitic because yeah it
made their hate Sound more professional and at
that time in Nazi Germany um you know from late
1800s through early 1900s you know that movement
uh developed as specific hatred towards the Jews
and so they applied I do I've heard of you heard
of this one heard that I've heard yeah yeah I've
heard a couple things so they started to use the
term anti-semitic in regards to specifically
hatred towards the Jews they popularized that
term by self-identifying and so the term became
popularized by the Nazis as anti-semitic means
hatred towards the Jew so it's a racist term it's
a racist term to start and then it became uh more
specific in its racism spread and popularized by
even more racism and then the it started out being
anti-jewish and anti-arab hate and then got named
as just anti-jewish hate and the anti-arab or the
Arab solidarity all that got left out so as a
racist that became exclusionary double racist
double racist so basically what you're saying is
we need to go back to the more inclusionary at
least go back to inclusionary races anti-semitic
is only getting part of the situation it's
semi citic and that's why we're here on Friday
night semites to make sure that uh everybody's
exclusionary racm becomes a little more
cross-pollinated intersectional if you will our
guest is amazing tonight uh she's recently been
stirring up a lot of controversy on podcast so we
figured we could use the Buzz too let's all bring
out our friend Amanda seals hilarious welcome to
the show what going welcome to the show yeah we do
whatever you want whatever you want yeah welcome
to the show for coming how you feeling take a sip
so um you bring up the saucer too is there honey
uh uh we shoot that's something we didn't think
about it's the first episode you just dip some
bcla in it and uh so yeah we do have it Friday
night we got uh some treats for everybody you know
we got a little Falafel some Dom some Baka what do
you call you Baka Baka yeah I'm working on it and
then uh of course uh to round out our citic meal
tonight some mango mango I beat the mango a little
bit for everybody yeah well I'm from Grenada so I
feel like that's really for me it's crosscultural
in all the ways well thank you for for being here
and and being being willing to be the first in our
garage I mean I'm honored yeah are you I am I mean
I'm not big on black firsts but I'll take this
one well yeah we I mean we're very we're big
fans of of a lot of the work you've done and
a lot of people know you know how active you
are on many issues but I am curious how you
got involved in the Palestine issue in 2021 when
I was still in my house uh because I don't know
if you did you hear about the pandemic issue no
no we've been in the garage since I see I can
see how that could happen um so my stepmother is
Palestinian oh wow but that never resonated like
it was never presented to me as like this is a
thing that we need to be learning and knowing
about and I won't say that I got to spend a
lot of time with my stepmother as an adult
but my sisters and my brothers of course are
AFR Palestinian and um my sister Netta who is
my like Spirit just in another body um she also
like had never and she explained to me later she
was like yeah we just never talk about being
Palestinian because it it's not it was like
okay you know you always are facing some type
of backlash you know you could be at your job
and get fired from your job etc etc now Mark
Lamont Hill is a good friend of mine and he's
always been involved uh since I've known him in
the Palestine movement but again it was never
really contextualized for me as something I
needed to know about which is what I think
a lot of black people in America feel they're
like oh that's something that's happening over
there like even with Mark it was like oh I guess
he's just like into Middle Eastern studies like
that's where my ignorance had led me right
and then also I have a lot of Jewish people
around me um but too yes yeah yeah yeah I got
a couple yeah a few a few um me too yeah hey
in but I didn't know that I had zionists around
me because that was not a term that had been
contextualized for me before either uh and so
when uh the annual attack Ona mosque happened
in 2021 again we were all in the house and so I
think that because folks were not as distracted
there was allowed for it allowed for there to be
more of a ground a ground swell of information and
I remember specifically also that being a year
after BLM and during black lives matter I got I
think I just entered into a different people's
timelines than I was before because of my out
spokenness around the black lives matter movement
and I say that because I went from just being like
this person who be talking stuff and who's
funny and who's on a TV show to for a lot of
people like oh this is somebody who is a social
justice Advocate who's informed Etc and so then
when this happened those same people who saw
me advocating so much for BLM in many ways were
Palestinians saying well you need to be advocating
for us too and I will say that I definitely had
um yeah I'm going to use this wording had fallen
prey to the miss nomer that questioning anything
around uh Jewish um involvement with Zionism
was anti-semitic right because this is now me
learning like oh what is Zionism right then uh I
had people around me telling me like you shouldn't
be asking about you shouldn't be looking into this
is way too difficult for you which let me tell you
something the best way to get me to learn about
something don't do it don't do it don't do it's
not even don't do it it's tell me I'm too dumb
to do it cuz now I'm just going to be Petty it's
really complicated yeah you can't you can't grasp
it what that is now Petty intellectualism now
I'm going to learn it just to go [ __ ] yourself
like so I also have a masters in African-American
studies so I mean I'm also academically trained
trained in identifying white [ __ ] yeah so I mean
that's a skill that I paid a lot of money to to
be able to do like on an academic scholarly level
so it took me approximately 7 minutes and maybe
42 seconds to be able to say oh this is white
[ __ ] like that's what's happening in Palestine
like this is yall said it was complicated yeah it
took some people 75 years so listen so that was
the beginning uh I dropped a couple friends and
then I started following I on Palace and began to
bring Palestine into my Consciousness on a daily
basis and yeah following I on Palestine it's very
hard to not do that and that's the thing like you
you needed to do that because you need to have
that Consciousness and America is so effective
at keeping our blinders on to uh you know really
just invoke this narcissistic culture America is a
narcissistic culture that really teaches you that
this is the best place in the world even though
there's nothing supporting that aside from access
to fast food and um like Skittles but like candy
I would say honestly the best part of America
is we have a lot of good candy we got good hot
C High frose cont but I just say all that to say
that my sister did an episode of my podcast small
doses okay at that time and when I asked her to
do it she was hesitant at first because of what
the environment has been for so long around being
Palestinian the backlash and right she's like you
know I don't want to lose my job and that was also
contextual I was like I didn't even know that it's
goes down like that I'm actually impressed I
did not push her and I'm a pushy broad I did
not push her and she came back and was like man
[ __ ] that let's do this [ __ ] and and you're
like that's the energy I need now let's go I never
knew how much I miss oh wow and um and so she did
the episode and it was so incredibly Illuminating
for not just myself but for my audience we even
replayed it post October 7th because it still rang
true you know she talks about her grandfather and
the neba and you know they're leaving hia
and I think for a lot of people that heard
that interview it really helped to contextualize
Palestine Beyond a political headline but as a
personal experience and because she's my sister
then they have a relativism to it because it's
like oh well she knows somebody that's just one
degree so post October 7th I will say that a lot
of what just drove the loud activism Beyond just
being a humanitarian was again just being incensed
at the gaslighting mhm this the willful effort
to to to convince people that what's happening
is not happening right and uh when you know
you have a platform of 2.3 million people and
you know that you have an ability to really like
break things down you just feel compelled to have
to keep doing this until more and more people get
it what were some of the myths like you said pre
2021 you know like what were some of the ideas in
your head like you know I grew up uh you know I
grew up in a Jewish family but not the mainstream
Zion his family but I still heard a lot of things
I'm curious like I'm always curious folks outside
of the as like just a fun place to go it's just a
party on the beach the only two contexts I've
heard about Israel were like oh my God Israel
has like amazing beaches right and can you imagine
living in Israel can you imagine living in Israel
and and having to hear sirens because of the
bombs every day like so it's only those two
context and you know of course I'm a sympathetic
like uh empathetic person so I'm like oh my God I
can't I can't imagine but I'm not even asking the
question well what why they got so much boms going
on um beaches and whose beaches are they whose
beaches are there who yeah whose beaches um what
[ __ ] on these beaches what [ __ ] what [ __ ]
took these beaches but you know um America has
been so effective in its suppression of knowledge
I'm a really smart person and I have learned more
since October 7th than I have learned in the last
seven years that's real like genuinely I became
an incredibly like I became radicalized within a
matter of two months and when I say radicalized
it's only because the norm is to not know [ __ ]
and to be cool with that right so at this point
literally like wanting to access more information
for the sake of dismantling the you know
government all you became a Jihadi on knowledge
yes yes I became a Jihadi on knowledge in
in you know it's it's just I have no tolerance
for stupidity and I learned recently with my
hanging out with us we appreciate we appreciate
the exception to the rule I used to think that
that made me elitist and as I've learned more
about my neurod Divergence I come I've come to
understand that that's actually a part of my
neurod Divergence like I just can't stomach
willful like the logic the linear way my mind
works it like it [ __ ] with me like it literally
like [ __ ] with like my internal me well this
this issue is the worst then cuz it's like all
the contradictions all the hypocrisies like you
said like what's the myth like I mean one of the
myths that I feel was very present for me was
that again that Israel was this like Safe Haven
and that that was okay right mhm cuz that's the
thing because then you get tricked into feeling
like you can't counter that or else you are now
anti-semitic and at the end of the day any place
that is only okay for some is not okay right
period well that's yeah so thanks for having me
course no that's uh I'll Take You Just Dropped
a Bomb inside of our minds um so it should be
that simple though right yeah it should be so
here's the like one of the contradictions which
we were talking about earlier which is not just
around Israel Palestine but America's own [ __ ]
and mythologies like around free speech and it's
like there's free speech and then you get anywhere
close to Palestine and Israel and then it's like
oh no no no no no no no no no and so I'm curious
what has your experience been I mean it's it goes
not just from art to entertainment but it's also
you've got 20 states that have passed laws
just even advocating for boycotting divestment
sanctions against Israel not even doing it but
advocating speech to non-violently protest so
what do you speak out on a lot of issues does
it feel different like the Free Speech issues
is it the same is it different it is different
in the sense that I've never had anyone tell me
very specifically don't say this thing right
it's it's more so just been like can you not
be political in right yeah like can we just have
a more light-hearted I'm like every time someone
does that I'm like why did you hire me why did you
hire me have you checked me out yeah like cuz it's
not going to be the funniest joke of the night is
not going to be about like mustard um I hope not
I go to Williamsburg but even when my agents you
know were having these weird conversations about
like you know I just feel like some of your posts
are anti-semitic I'm like which on well I haven't
seen all of them and you've never said anything to
me about anything ever before right on my internet
and I have absolutely on my Instagram talked about
a mil of things uh you know I have College dates
where I've had them reach out to my business
relations manager and say hey we just want to
make sure that Amanda's not going to talk about
XYZ yeah and Palestine or other stuff Palestine
no we just want to make sure going talk about
Palestine that's the XYZ yeah yeah yeah a man's
not going to talk about Palestine you know she's
not going to say the word don't already know it's
a college like uh she's not going to say the word
genocide like so like even something so specific
as a word uh I've never experienced that before
and I think it's it is worth noting though like
so y'all had no problem with me saying stuff about
the black people right with me saying stuff about
black lives matter with me saying stuff about that
and I think it's really genuinely because that is
not going to disrupt our country's status quo it's
not and wish I know we like to think it will it's
not what's happening now is there is an actual
disruption that is uh creating Fishers in this
Foundation built on Israel is something that we
need to protect As Americans and the 51st state
it's it's I mean the one that you can't make fun
of right and and as we know whoever you can't make
make fun of is is who has you by the balls yeah
like that's who it is all of that is so bizarre
to really witness I mean free speech when people
would typically be talking about Free Speech
they'd be like I mean it's free speech I can say
what I want on your page and I'm like no no that's
not what Free Speech means like you can say what
you want on my page and then I'll block you like
you don't have the freedom to just come from my
neck yeah uh but now we're seeing like the actual
uh subversion of free speech in the Constitution
which is no I could I can talk without y'all
arresting me and they're like no no except not
not here yeah and that's uh very frightening yeah
so you you I mean you're somebody who's seen to
some degree the inside of Hollywood I mean you've
had success in La you've you've done well for
your career you've had agents why some degree
like why you trying to shave me you know what I'm
saying why you trying to minimize my actually I
I a good way if I was like you're Mrs Hollywood
out here like I would be like get this [ __ ]
guy out of here who is this guy yeah because I've
said that to people before they're like come on
I'm not like I'm you know you're not part of the
Hollywood establishment you know I mean yeah I am
not so you've seen the inside uh of Hollywood in
a lot of regards you you've lived the Hollywood
Life agents managers and stuff you already kind
of gave us you know a little bit but like how has
that changed since you've been more outspoken I
don't have any agents anymore of course none of
them are going to tell you explicitly right uh but
one of my agents who I consider a friend he voiced
concern and then you know to his credit he was
like I don't have a problem working with you but
then at that point I said well I have a problem
now because this isn't going to get better MH he
is Jewish I don't think he identifies as like
I'm a Zionist but he also doesn't identify as
not and I said honestly there's only three you're
either a Zionist an anti-zionist or you're in the
middle and if you're in the middle then you might
as well be in that first bucket because you're
supporting by your silence and I don't want to be
in a scenario where you're having to negotiate how
you negotiate for me yeah um and so we parted ways
amicably a few months later after I signed my book
deal my book agent drop me which is like after
the deal yeah and so and doesn't take Commission
this is how I know that it's yes because like
I'm working and I told her straight up like
quit bullshitting me like you you know it's
insulting to me for you to be bullshitting me
like you don't know me like we have enough of an
of a relationship but you know people choose the
Empire all the time so that was that and then my
other agent who's not even at the agency anymore
she was like you know you're just you're on a
list and uh you know this this is a list the
list doesn't have a heading it's just the people
that we have to let go um but was interesting
though was that in in both of the cases of Jewish
agents that had dropped me they weren't aligning
themselves to the deplorable language that we see
coming from people like Deborah Messing etc etc
but I was able to I feel like inform them about
some of their own histories because of me doing my
own research you know and you start to understand
how so many folks are really just kind of SHP put
through into these political ideologies by Family
by Legacy Etc without them even really knowing
until something like this happens where you end
up having to choose a side based on what are my
actual individual values not just the values that
have been passed down to me I mean I cried because
you are used to a certain format of things that
you think is what is necessary for you to like
function but I I very quickly was reentered in
knowing that this is pushing me in a direction
that feels intuitively correct I've been telling
people that I'm divesting from celebrity and what
I mean mean by that is that being in the Hollywood
Belly of the Beast does require and in some cases
you do sign a form but some cases you it's an
unsigned it's an un it's a unspoken commitment to
upholding certain things and to being quiet about
certain things and even like the upholding of like
why do managers just get 10% cuz they show up yeah
right why I don't know I've been asking my manager
Sammy why why is taking my 10% doesn't make let's
move on let's move on but like stuff like that
is very much like it's just accepted and it's
nonsense I had to actually actively disrupt my
own things that I like align to and I'm in the act
of that right now and even like being on a podcast
like this like there's me I'm also having to be
more responsible and conscious about the spaces
that I want to be in because let's examine that
let's examine that this is why you need manager
that's how we got you because you inadvertently
uphold the same [ __ ] that you're against just by
showing up what's interesting obviously whenever
we're talking about Hollywood as a Jewish Lefty
film adjacent person uh people are like how do you
deal with Hollywood to me and uh I have not been
on that type of list but I've been on other lists
I've been for speaking out on Israel Palestine
I've been put on What's called the the self-hating
Israel threatening Jewish list it's the Jewish
[ __ ] list self hating is real threatening but
then when it comes to Hollywood people are like
well how do you deal with that Josh and the thing
about uh cuz they're like uh you know you got to
be careful and don't play into the Trope of
you know Hollywood's controlled by the Jews
I'm like no it's not because I've been trying to
make a movie for a long time no one's giving me
you know the movie no one I'm still waiting for my
bank I'm still waiting for my media company all my
stereotypes I'm waiting to happen I haven't got
them yet but the thing about free speech that's
interesting like when around Israel Palestine
the I think a lot about McCarthyism and this
is the new McCarthyism and when you think about
Hollywood and McCarthyism what it often was in the
blacklisted writers and the the Hollywood 10 and
all of that it was often the blacklisted writers
and actors and directors were often left they were
all Lefty but they were often Jewish radicals and
they were being blacklisted by Jewish conservative
Studio bosses interesting and people don't talk
about that oh yeah Meer and all the heads of all
these ones they were conservative I mean they were
conservative capitalists what was the reason that
they were turning on their own oh because it was
McCarthyism anti-communism they wanted to be SE
seen as patriotic good Americans good Americans
not those Russians yeah they didn't even think
of it as selling out they didn't think of the the
Jewish radicals as their people they thought of
them as communist traitors because Russia also did
a whole expulsion of the Jews and they felt like
that was them supporting the [ __ ] that's a whole
another yeah I mean it goes in multiple levels but
my point is that like this thing of that there's
one demographic group and one demographic
group has one idea or ideology is [ __ ] and
that is an example of like puncturing that myth
because you have like we have a phrase two Jews
three opinions like we disagree on everything
the problem is on Israel they try to make it
so it's one opinion Israel from Hebrew means to
wrestle with like not physically wrestle but like
to debate to struggle you either say wrestle with
God wrestle with each other the best Jewish [ __ ]
is we're yelling debating and disagreeing with
each other that's all we have done for thousands
of years yeah with you know some bagels and some
things and on this they want to silence the debate
you at least need to tell me where you stand but
a lot of people they get scared but it's often
not even their own fear they're using someone
else's fear as an excuse and I'm like stand on
your own [ __ ] so you're actually stand on
your own [ __ ] you're saying it's actually
anti-israel to criticize to to shut down debate
about Israel damn right is saying it's it's it's
anti-jewish it's anti-jewish it's anti-semitic to
squash debate on Israel it's not yeah I'm saying
cult they take it all the way that's one thing
I will give Zion is they are committed okay that
is a committed cause people out there tell your
significant others you commit like a Zionist okay
get down on your knees put that ring out and you
commit like for 75 years or more yeah yeah yeah
oh God it's for the wrong reasons but I think that
you are a you know a great example to celebrities
who are again for the wrong reasons celebrities
are scared he meant that as a compliment yeah
my phrasing seems to be coming out as I'm just
listening I just these these celebrity the whole
idea of celebrity is also like just some [ __ ]
[ __ ] at this point because it's not it used to
mean a celebrated person M mhm and typically like
someone is being celebrated if I look back at the
80s like celebrities where people who actually
like did something forbid for the most part like
Stallone even Princess D was actively doing things
for AIDS research and for landmines like she was
actively using her celebrity for good right for
landmines or against landmines for I just want
I'm justess I'm just saying I'm just saying yeah
like remember she like walked through a landmine
like to to like get people to know like no this
[ __ ] is real I mean this whole Israel Palestine
situation is really land mines you know what I'm
saying oh god wow yeah it was right there you had
to do it you had to do yes I would actually look
down on deserves that deserves a little mango
but I just say that to say that at this point
I'm like you where I'm like well if you are a
celebrity then you have responsibility because
now you have platform and so with that platform
there should be some level of regard that you're
using that for Beyond just promoting your your
stuff right but then you have other people who are
like no that's actually not necessary celebrities
are really just people who we want to escape with
right right bread in circuses right yeah so DJ
call let me let me ask this forget the celebrity
[ __ ] as an artist like as an artist imperative
so so want to ask actually it's for both of you
guys I want to ask not just as an artist but in
particular as a comedian like what is the role
of the artist the comedian during a war during
during a genocide you guys are hitting stages
across the country what is people are like how
do you laugh during this [ __ ] now you know I'm
Jewish we come from Gallows humor is part of our
thing um but like I mean I'm black like that's
all we're doing too they in the fields like haa
so I mean if you can come up with jokes in
the cotton baby what you talking about I
mean I don't know I feel like Sammy I just feel
like it depends on the type of because the type
of person you are is the type of comedian you
are for sure right so it's not enough to just
say as a comedian I mean I think ultimately it's
what kind of person are you I don't consider all
comedians artists okay there's that shots
fir names names but I also don't consider
people brave for sure and I think it would
be a lot easier to talk about something that
so for instance like talking about 911 in the
context of those are bad guys like that for a
comedian is low hanging fruit because like that
was the consensus right but at this point we're
in a time where like we've talked about with the
Free Speech if you're going to like speak about
this you already know that there's going to be
possible backlash you also know that you're up
against ignorance for sure so as a comic that
also means like damn these people might not
laugh you got you got the education but to
get the punchline if Comics knew that they
would get laugh then they would say they just
wouldn't that's the only reason yeah I mean I
walked three white people the other day cuz by the
third time I said colonizer they were like ah we
didn't come here for this there a three colonizer
maximum drink minimum yeah three colonizer maximum
that's the official maximum these days so I just
um yeah I mean I also feel like the more that
we've gotten into this world that is so artists
are so accessible remember before like your art
spoke for you right right right and now it's
not just your art like you speak for you who
you follow speaks for you I mean someone dm' me
today like I see that you follow so and so and I
just wanted you to know XYZ I'm like I didn't even
know I followed in I get those messages and cuz
I'm sure I'm following like bleeding heart Zion
people like why do you follow Michael Rapaport
for material bro I got a job to do so I I just uh
Nuance has become so real like Nuance has become
nuanced at this point and Nuance is controversial
it really is how dare you it's very how dare you
point out this very important Illuminating factor
and difference right but I will say that for me I
am always and have always been uh an artist
who believes that art should be Illuminating
art should be benevolent you know it's it's a
conversation between me and my audience it's
not just some uh it's not just me jacking off at
my own creative ability like that doesn't really
serve and so well speak for yourself but I will
say that I'm going to counter that but I I mean
at this point I'm like create like so when I was
in school I created my own major yeah they didn't
have one they didn't have a black Studies major I
created my own major and that's what I'm doing at
this point in my life like I I don't even want
the title of comedian anymore I'm like I am an
artistic intellectual I use humor to educate
and entertain that's it and you know if if I
if I continue on this path in the most honest and
committed way possible I hope that I craft a new
pathway for people for artists to commit to you
know cuz I don't I I haven't had a blueprint to
follow in this journey as a as an active artist
and activist because usually it's like one gives
way to the other yeah you can't do it both you
want the both ends break the false binaries I
mean Nina Nina Simone is is one is one but you
know you look at Baldwin and for what it's worth
like a lot of Baldwin's writing happened and then
he you know really had his um his radicalism and
that's when you see like the fire time and but he
also had to deal with folks being like Oh you're
not our little darling black boy anymore you
actually know [ __ ] and you're talking about
the government and that was the whole reason why
we brought you to this Iowa Writers Workshop so
that you would learn not how to talk about like
we didn't want you talking about the government
um look that up form form form yes let's talk
about like you know just being people and the
difficulty of being people not the realities that
the government makes it difficult for some people
to be people than it does for others the [ __ ]
the [ __ ] they teach in those writers workshops
cuz I've been in those is the opposite way they
they say be as specific as possible tell your
story write the [ __ ] no one else can you can
tell about you but then when you talk about it
where you talk about either Blackness Palestinian
identity you know whatever you want to say crazy
Jewish [ __ ] um they're like no no let's get
a little more Universal and you know what that
is that's just bad writing like you know you got
the more specific comes the universal but think
about that it's the same with Hollywood it's this
idea that we want stories we want stories but we
really don't like we want an Asian family that
acts like every other family but like has Asian
touches we want a black family that has like you
know little black quirks but it's still a black
family like when you look at like fresh off the
boat you look at blackish like you look at even
The Cosby Show like these are all still like we
are a wholesome family that is pushing forwards
this nuclear family construct um even Modern
Family is still like we are a nuclear like
here's a husband here's a wife like so these
tropes are not by accident right that's why
I never I never made it in Hollywood I never it
never clicked for me because well that's one of
seven reasons why I never made it in Hollywood
uh is that they they always wanted this Trope
of of a family when when when deciding what your
sitcom would be and my family is just so atypical
like they can't really be described by tropes so
every time I pitch something they just it didn't
hit with them like we have something that fits a
little bit more then I started to make it on my
own um but I I you know I started talking about
paline a lot more than I had even previously and
then I was like you know what things are going
well on my own so I might as well just build
my own thing where I don't have to be constrained
to tropes or expectations I've had to just commit
to being okay with being um not a selfish artist
but a self-sufficient artist like the ecosystem of
Amanda is enough and get tricked into feeling
like no like I need to have a platform that's
giving everybody else a platform and it becomes
very very hard to do that because honestly this
this Hollywood system has tricked everybody into
not trusting right and so you try and work with
other people but then they start looking at
you now that you're like the source they look
at you like your NBC and then they start being
like where's the money and and you're like oh
you know what I'm not them I'm not them that's
why I thought you was over here so I've had to
really just commit myself s to being Tyler Perry
in the uh self-sufficient but like with good
wigs so you went to Colombia I did go to
Colombia for grad for grad and how so how
how how like you know in the recent event
how has this all felt to you what what are
your what are your thoughts I uh was so and
just engorged with joy yeah at seeing these
students students at Columbia really be not just
loud but defiant and unwavering yeah unwavering
and then to see it just Domino across the globe
to it's still going yeah um and then even to my
undergrad on a mo Sunni purchase and they
actually were able to get convers shout
out to the state school cuz everyone always
talks about Harvard Yale whatever I like to
hum state I'm saying
affordable yeah Phoenix University not too many
doing you sitting on the couch right here yo yeah
ask yourself what SCH are you going to um so
I just got the honor of hosting the people's
graduation which was a ceremony that was done
in um New York I saw that yeah yeah at Columbia
and uh well adjacent four Columbia students and
faculty who were a part of this movement IMC the
event but you know we had Nora erat there and Mona
shalabi and Adrian Marie Brown I mean it was just
a really beautiful space to be in and to be able
to shine light on these students who you know have
really put their Futures in Jeopardy and they're
really is no excuse to not support them period
yeah and that's why when you see me loudly saying
that about people that I know um people are like
oh you know you shouldn't be choosing opinion over
friendship I'm I'm I'm like at what point did you
all become so [ __ ] me mouthed that there's an
opinion to be had on whether or not sh students
should be able to peaceful protest without being
attacked by hundreds of police and riar that's
an opinion like at certain point it's just like
no a fact that that shouldn't happen period even
constitutionally that just shouldn't happen um and
all the conservatives always saying free speech on
campus free speech on campus and then I mean the
conservatives are liars they're also like small
government but give me your uterus um or else
yeah um uterus is a small government oh God come
on nothing ah we love you s a lot go on in there
we we love a lot goes on in there I'm let a real
jurisdiction that no one I'm not saying anybody
specific owns it I'm just saying the universe
itself as a who possesses a uterus I can tell you
it is dysfunctional like our government I mean you
really you never know which way it's going to
go that was very generous I was just given the
Prem generous I will tell you that you really
never know which way things are going to things
are going to go but yeah so that I mean I I uh I
got to go to the encampment and I say I got to go
because I consider it to be an honor to be able to
be welcomed into that space someone I know who's
in government went to one of the encampments and
she was very upset that they she wasn't received
cuz she actually comes from organizing and she was
like you know I I followed all the instructions
and and I showed up and I I got iced man like
they was really not feeling me and I was like
yeah cuz you were op um and she was like no what
do you mean and I was like you know I [ __ ] with
you heavy but once you go in them doors you up
you might be the less opy of the Ops but you a
op be and she was like o this was an Illuminating
conversation hey that's that's the new lesser of
two evils the less opy of the op the L opy of
the Ops yeah I like it but I I I uh I had to
ask myself too what I have been doing this were I
here yeah uh and I think that really is something
we should all be asking ourselves two questions
we should always be asking ourselves when we see
these things is like would I be doing it and if
Harriet tman came back would she shoot me like
these are the two questions I feel like everyone
should ask themselves curi was shooting anybody
apparently she was shooting anybody who was going
to turn back right or who got too scared right
MH so you got to ask yourself is she cocking
a pistol my way and if so it's time to go to
therapy at least to a hard jog around the block
yeah yeah we've got the couch for the therapy we
got the couch for the therapy I want to ask a a
different question um cuz I know you're a hip-hop
head I am I don't I don't know if you saw memore
as the person coming to drop the this this is you
know like I'm not going to lie to you break it
down because when I saw I started when I started
watching the video I wanted to hate it okay like
and I don't even have anything against Ben but I
just was like here oh he put his government name
out here okay okay okay okay I'm like here we go
yeah people put on a cier want to rap um and then
like you know 16 bars in I was like this actually
pretty solid not bad not bad not bad so I had to
DM him and I was like good [ __ ] bro he's like
thank you Amanda you call me Ben did he that's
Lally his name Emoji I want to say he to say um
did you did you say you should have won the Grammy
he's like he's a cool dude I mean I think for what
it's worth I mean it's great it's great it it
was it's overdue I mean as a hip-hop head I'm
I'm wholly horrified by the complete dir yeah of
Music addressing any form of this there you go
and then you had Drake and Kendrick and people
are like oh you're not really a hip-hop head
because you're not really into this and I was
like I just maybe I'm a purist uh but I can't
see value in watching two billionaires gossip
about each other on wax in the context of what's
happening right now like if that was maybe a year
ago and everything wasn't as in the face uh could
maybe you know kind of give in but at this point
I'm just like this is not interesting yeah and I
love Kendrick and I tolerate Drake I mean for for
M lore what what I love is like you look at his
Evolution and 2014 10 years ago you know the the
one that the like liberal the nice white liberal M
LaMore he's like Same Love it's like I'm Pro gay
marriage but I'm not gay you know like that was
basically he was like she's like he like what you
guys are doing what you guys are doing not support
it I don't want to do it myself but you know what
hey kiss away and from that to 10 years later he's
like we need a worldwide Revolution like like that
I mean Len I'll take I'll take it Mac I did Beth
um I did a documentary last year called in Amanda
we trust it's a political comedy documentary I did
this based on my feeling like not enough people
are curious enough about how our government
actually functions in order to be able to shift
it right but that is still a reformist perspective
because it still assumes that it's going to
require being a part of government to change
it and it wasn't until post October 7th that I
just between I mean you read enough gome Chomsky
and you're like what are we doing uh but you
really start to understand that there's so much
that you just don't know uh and once you start
to really open your mind to that which is what
I've really been trying to encourage my audience
to do is to open their mind to even just knowing
how much they don't know so many people feel so
confident about what they think this is that it
hampers your ability to actually be an effective
disruptor and I had to so I can see how that
could happen in even that amount of time since
it happened to me within a matter of 6 months
I mean part of why we're doing this is like even
when we agree uh there's still a lot to learn um
ohm and so so I I want to I'm going to just share
something I don't know I see the cfia over there
so I know maybe y'all can break it down uh I know
there's like the black and white CFA there's the
red and white cfia if you see that run I'm just
kidding no like literally so originally I red
and white cfia was more like Saudi Arabia but I
have a CFA from Palestine that is red and white
but then like this became the symbol yeah like a
cfia is a cfia right you know and then it's who
is it made by where is it made but then there's
the symbol and then within the cfia like there's
things that have different meaning right so like
this is represents the uh the fishing you know the
Waters of CLA bring out front let's let's take
a look this is important cuz I think this is
the [ __ ] that we're talking about stripes mean
but to me but to my knowledge this represents the
the olive trees do you get people like when you
rock a cfia do people say stuff for the most part
people say thank you for your support for the
most part I was on a flight yeah oh well that's
always a good place I was on a flight wearing my
cfia and I it was uh this woman and then her two
kids were sitting across from us in the aisle I
mean so across the aisle from us and her daughter
was like this is the nicest plane I've ever been
on and so I was just laughing because I made ey
contact with her because like her daughter was
just like so Overjoyed so we started chuckling
and then she like like had a switch the woman or
the dog the woman okay and so this four-year-old
was like oh no oh no I'm scared yeah um and so
the woman says you know I'm Jewish oh God so are
is it going to be a problem for you sitting next
to me and I was like well I mean I didn't know
you were Jewish until literally this second but
also are you Zionist well I'm Jewish so of course
some Zionist and I was like yeah that's not how it
works uh plenty of Jewish people are not zionists
she was like well is it going to be a problem or
not you're the one who brought it up and I said
you know ma'am the problem is the genocide not us
sitting next to each other and she was like and
she got up in a huff and she took her zaring ass
down the uh aisle and she got them to change her
seat her three people had to move to accommodate
her pseudo fear and her irrational fear apparently
she then like cuz I didn't even show her face
but of course I showed the interaction yeah and
um so you got a Zionist to move I know I stood
my ground uh nice and she I was going to say I
don't know how you say Karen in Hebrew but I'll
learn Z yeah oh you got it Zin and then like the
flight attendant who moved her like she tried to
be snippy with me and I had to look at her like
dead in her eyes like is this what you want to do
is this like is is it what you want to do then the
next flight attendant came and I said that flight
attendant is very disrespectful and she came back
very different would you like a bis c um yes I
would actually make it too but I that was the
only time I've ever had was this first class by
the way yeah I guess I was a dumb question that
there's there's very few things that I don't play
about and first class is one of them when you fly
as much as I fly like I really yeah first class
going to teach you for the the next time that
happens the the yid I don't know the Hebrew the
Yiddish to use for anyone who needs Shanda it
means shame oh not Shanda Ry Shand exactly it's
going to it's going to confuse her so much Shanda
oh oh that's perfect that's just like my mother
so that'll be great yeah it like when I said
I wasn't going to be a doctor my mom Shanda but
you know what what you going to do start a podast
instead so just throw a little [ __ ] yish at them
it'll mind [ __ ] them so much they w't know what
to do with the CL okay Shand yeah there you go yes
because I you know the the yish word that always
throws me I just feel like mench sounds like a
bad person oh it's the best but it's the best
I such a you're a mench yeah yeah it's well here's
the thing we were talking about yish earlier which
is it comes Yiddish comes from a combination of
Hebrew but also German and Slavic languages so
the ones that don't sound so good like mench is
also how you say man in German it's a German is
it real so it comes out like uber mench nii all
that [ __ ] so but like mench I you know that one
that's like the highest compliment you can give
someone what does it mean exactly it means human
but it's like the best of a human being so it's
like it's like you know Einstein mench Malcolm X
mench like like this was you know uh these are
the true our best if the aliens came down we'd
be like this gu yeah I'm sure Malcolm would have
loved that I said no it's see learning no in my
family it's almost never for men okay in my family
it's never men so it's unisex but for me a unisex
word is [ __ ] um like men are [ __ ] we get that
the men get that in my family too yeah for sure
yeah the women are the Menches the men are the
Uber [ __ ] yes all right all right thanks Mom
so do you feel like as you have committed to
I'm just going to be on my own route do you
feel liberated in that or do you 100% tell me
more 1,00% I mean I I always felt like I want
to you know I want to get good at the craft and
I want to ride you know play the Hollywood system
and get a show or get on TV I don't know if you
had the same goals but that was kind of like I'm
just going to work the system I'm going to do
what everybody says it's what you do you make
a tight seven you perform you get on Montreal Just
for Laughs you get on late night you get your own
sitcom and then you know maybe do a writer room
for a little bit and then you get in the movies
and then stand up yeah and I was like that was the
game that was laid out but when I started back in
2007 and then as I went through the steps you have
to hear the the the game kept changing the system
kept like the go post moved social media the DIY
mentality totally it kept growing and growing and
growing until I had these Lost Years where like
I had I was repped for a little while I had some
buds and then they all dropped me and then why
did they drop you uh I don't I don't know they
just felt like R his I wasn't lucrative I wasn't
lucrative and and I mean I think in in their
defense I think that I I hit it a little bit too
early I don't think I was ready I think I didn't
have all the ideas I needed to I didn't think I
had the skill set I disagree I think he was ready
they were not ready for him that's friend you know
what it was also the time that I started talking
about Palestine publicly there was a little bit of
that overlap but but you know whatever that's just
conspiracy so then I had these Lost Years where I
was just like I'm going I got to figure this out
on my own and work hard and then I got on Netflix
and then the pandemic happened and then so I was
like okay the timing is whatever and then so when
the pandemic happened as you know through through
the pandemic like the industry kind of fell fell a
lot of it fell apart I mean it's still functional
but at that point the model was you can just put
your Clips on social media and build your own fan
base so that's just what I did started getting
the fan base and now like I don't even think
about Hollywood I don't even and it's like if I
want to be in a movie I could just make a movie
dope yeah so it's it's completely liberating do
you feel like other Comics get it when you tell
them this yeah I well it's to a degree I feel like
most Comics are now aware that like you can make
it under that that model you know um I think a
lot of them are still chasing the the industry
dream school dream you know I think those are
people who are either they they started in the
time where it was still functioning or like they
still see it and they want to be a part of it but
I think most people kind of know now I do think
there is something to be said though for having a
certain like self fortification where you aren't
requiring the studios to affirm you yeah um and
there's still a lot of that I've noticed like this
feeling like yeah I could do it by myself but that
doesn't mean it's going to be at the same level
as this and so then it's not as valuable whereas
I'm like if I did that [ __ ] by myself it's it's
more valuable for sure whenever I talk about my
documentary which you can get on my patreon and
you can go to uh inand trust.com when I talk about
my documentary it's like no I I always I'm like
no I made this with my money I made this with all
of my own money I had to figure this whole [ __ ]
out from the top to bottom and therefore it is far
more valuable because I didn't have a whole staff
sure you know that was committed to this project
I try and cultivate that if you can rely on you
then the rest of this stuff is just and especially
now if you're going to be somebody who stands for
something you better be able to rely on you and at
this point I just feel like Beyond being someone
who uses humor I really just think we're so far
behind those of us with good hearts are so far
behind the evil for sure it's like there's only
six members of the Jedi Council yeah that's what
it feels like it's like the Empire done got the
whole [ __ ] Galaxy figured out and we're sitting
here at the Jedi Council like I guess we should
have trained more Jedi because how are going
to beat this and now we have to go through an
entire Clone War like that's where we are and no
yeah no one like that one so shout out to okatana
that is voiced by Ashley drain who went to high
school with me Dr Phillips forever but I use Star
Wars metaphors all the time because it's it's so
blatant that like that's really where we are we're
so far behind and people are still looking for
a Luke Skywalker it's like no everybody is going
to have to be a part of the [ __ ] Rebel Force
like everybody well and the [ __ ] metaphor got
Lost in Translation when George Lucas wrote Star
Wars the the Jedi the rebellions you know the the
rebels that was the Viet Kong that was a metaphor
for Vietnam and the Empire Darth Vader was the US
and everyone forgets that part and so we always
America in the movies we are the bad we we root
for the rebels in the movies and we don't realize
we're the empire in real life we're always the bad
guys and and we are the dark Force we are the Dark
Army we are Voldemort but the thing is I don't
know Patron them like I'm just we're always the
bad guys like in The Never Ending Story we're the
nothing oh we're going there oh man you get my 80s
Nostalgia all worked up here I forgot what talking
I mean it's just keep going yeah no I mean I think
the thing is if you're going to take that metaphor
which is there's always the way the Empire goes
down in Star Wars or any these movies is there's
people on the inside who flip and join the rebels
um there's always there's somebody who comes over
and you need those people and if we are within
the Empire but who came over I mean there's Lando
but he wasn't really down for anything except just
being the Fly Guy I guess I'm think of the new one
there was John boa and he came over you know what
I'm saying so but even that I'm going to challenge
you on okay all right all right challeng you I can
tell you really into the Star Wars end [ __ ] nerd
Jedi I can tell I've G yeah because you have to
understand stick to Safe topics like Palestine
and Israel okay because jamba's character was
not and he was not a part they messed him up
in the last couple ones but in the first one you
know no no no no no I'll break it down no because
he is only an imperial stor Trooper because
he as a child was kidnapped like from a from
a land from a planet where they had invaded and
so he just it was like being blah blah blah yeah
like it's just like he was it's like the rebel
troops who then are taking children from their
neighbor from their villages in the Congo and
Sudan and making them join to then hurt their
own people so he was not like there because
he unlike the the you know salt of the earth
Americans who are like I'm going to go fight for
Israel in the iof and it's like no that you youu
go back to New Jersey like so yeah I just want
to get that clear you know so we don't have any
receptions yeah yeah oh Star Wars we've cleared
up we cleared up if you want to get into Star
Trek we can do that too because I definitely
do not okay got it cool cool cool but I just
I I really do feel like what I'm trying to do on
a daily basis is get folks to acknowledge their
own ability to be leaders yeah whatever that
looks like like you don't have to be Malcolm
X but like you can be leading the conversation
at your dinner table that wouldn't have happened
before and I I know that and I know that may
sound like real like I don't know like woooo
or IDE ideological but I just think that in
order to actively pursue the learning that we
need to have in order to really challenge what's
happening you have to first believe that you can
do something about it cuz like humans need a
carrot to go towards yep and they've done such
a good job at numbing folks and like convincing
everyone that you don't got what it takes
less uh consuming and more being the protagonist
of the own stories like being the Agents of change
like marjie Taylor green uhoh believes that she
is the protagonist of her own story she believes
a lot of things what saying like these terrible
people that's the takeway that's the takeway for
the show it's true though these people they don't
question themselves there's nothing more confident
than a medoc white person like nothing I've met
a couple yeah they're like what I'm me and then
it's proven how do you think I got on this show
nice you marged your way into it damn damn you
well you know that in the that in the Jewish
face lasers you and your bleach blonde Butch
body on that note um oh lovely well I just want
to say thank you for coming on we appreciate you
I love we need more leaders we need more artists
who speak their mind and uh thank you for coming
through we appreciate you and we got your back
thank you and uh you like the chocolate by the
way the chocolate is delicious good yeah thanks
for hoarding that over there but I'll get someone
I can and you know beautiful a shirt from Matthew
and um we're in a real wild place where people
think their only way of being hurt is self-
imulation like that like that should let you
know how Wild [ __ ] is they're like you know
what only thing I can do is put myself on fire
like that's Bonkers it's either that or make a
Tik Tok video so like the fact that that is the
range lets us know that and the fact that that
that happens everybody's like what the [ __ ]
and then 3 Days Later business as usual that's how
numb people are self imulation is not even there's
been three there's been three yeah three and they
were all white people that's the other part I be
like white people setting themselves on fire y'all
don't care about that yeah well I'm definitely not
doing a hunger strike why y'all looking at me why
y look at me cuzz I'm like listen if y'all if the
white lives don't even matter y'all ain't going to
give a [ __ ] if I starve myself so you know but
it's it's really nice to be here I love the space
y'all are creating it's necessary it's needed and
uh thanks for having thanks for coming of course
happy Friday Friday night semi we out shukran